(upbeat music)
- Hello, English learners.
Welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're bringing you
another great lesson about appointments.
- That's right, we've
got an elementary lesson
about cancelling and appointments.
- It's a really common situation sometimes.
You have an appointment
at the doctors or something.
- Or at work, and you have to cancel it.
- Yes, so we're gonna
learn some great
language to help you
cancel appointments today.
Let's go straight to the dialogue then.
- We're going to be listening
as Samantha and Angela
have a phone conversation and
Angela is trying to cancel an appointment.
- And it's gonna be a little
bit fast in the beginning,
but when we come back, we will
explain all the great vocabulary.
(upbeat music)
- Hello, Samantha speaking.
- Hi Samantha, this is Angela calling.
- Oh, hi Angela, what's up?
- I'm just calling about our meeting today.
I wonder, is it possible to reschedule
our appointment in the afternoon?
I have a bit of an emergency
that I need to take care of.
- Let me see, it shouldn't
be too much of a problem.
- I'm really sorry.
I hope it doesn't
inconvenience you too much.
It's just this thing came up and.
- Angela, you know what?
I can't make it to our meeting either.
Why don't we postpone it
tomorrow afternoon at the same time?
- Sounds great, see you tomorrow.
- Angela, Angela look up.
See that lady over there who's
trying on a red leather jacket?
Isn't that Samantha?
- What?
- No wonder she told me she
couldn't make it to the meeting.
- Oh no, I think she saw me.
- Okay, we have some
really interesting words
that you probably listen to in this dialogue,
so let's start with language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
Today on language takeaway,
we're bringing you three words.
Erica, what's the first one?
- The first word is reschedule.
- Reschedule.
- When you reschedule an appointment,
you change it for another day or time.
- Exactly.
- Great, the second word
that we have is inconvenience.
- Inconvenience.
- So to inconvenience someone is to
make things not convenient for the person.
- So to make things a little bit difficult,
that's to make things a
little bit uncomfortable.
- Inconvenience.
- And our third word is.
- postponed.
- We have some examples
of the word postpone
that will help you to understand
its meaning a little bit better.
Let's listen.
- Example one.
- Since Robert is late again, we
have to postpone the meeting.
- Example two.
- I'm sorry Simon, but your vacation
has been postponed until next month.
- Example three.
- Unfortunately, the
flight will be postponed.
- Okay, so basically postponed is to delay.
- That's right.
- Make it at a later time.
- At a later time.
- Okay, some great words
there and we can listen
to our dialogue a second
time at a slower speed.
- Hello, Samantha speaking.
- Hi Samantha, this is Angela calling.
- Oh, hi Angela, what's up?
- I'm just calling about our meeting today.
- I wonder, is it possible to reschedule
our appointment in the afternoon?
I have a bit of an emergency
that I need to take care of.
- Let me see.
It shouldn't be too much of a problem.
I'm really sorry.
I hope it doesn't
inconvenience you too much.
It's just this thing came up end.
- Angela, you know what?
I can't make it to our meeting either.
Why don't we postpone it
tomorrow afternoon at the same time?
- Sounds great.
See you tomorrow.
- Angela, Angela, look up.
See that lady over there who's
trying on a red leather jacket?
Isn't that Samantha?
- What?
- No wonder she told me she
couldn't make it to the meeting.
- Oh no, I think she saw me.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so in this
dialogue, we had some really
great phrases that we should
look at in fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
- We have three
phrases for you today in
fluency builder, and the
first one is so common.
It's a great phrase.
What's up?
- What's up?
(laughing)
So this is a very common way of saying hi.
- Yeah, what's up?
- How's it going?
- What's going on?
- Right, and now the interesting thing
is that many people don't
know how to answer this phrase.
- Yes, I see this all the
time with my students.
- So if you say what's up,
you should say, - Not much.
- Not much.
- Nothing.
- So what's up?
- Not much.
(laughing)
- All right, so the next
time someone tells
you what's up, now you
know what to answer.
- Yeah.
- Okay, our second
phrase is, can't make it.
- Can't make it.
- I can't make it.
- We use this phrase when
we want to say I cannot attend.
- I cannot make it.
- Yeah, I can't come.
- Right, so if you're having a party today,
I say, oh, I'm sorry, I can't make it.
- Mm-hmm.
- It means I can't go.
- Exactly, maybe one more example.
So Marco, we've got a
meeting today at three o'clock.
- I can't make it.
I'm recording today.
- Oh, okay.
(laughing)
- So can't make it.
Our last word for fluency
builder, this thing came up.
- This thing came up.
This thing came up.
- This is a great way of giving an
excuse for why you can't make it.
- Right, so I can't make it today
because this thing came up.
Like, something happened.
- Something happened.
- Yeah, let's listen to
a few examples of this
phrase so we can see
how it's used in the wild.
- Example one, I'm sorry that I'm late.
This thing came up at work
and I had to stay to take care of it.
- Example two.
- I can't talk right now.
Something came up.
- Example three.
Sorry, I missed the
meeting, something came up.
- Okay, great example, then I
guess it's perfectly clear now.
- Yes.
- So let's listen to our
dialogue a third time
and now we're ready
to understand everything.
(upbeat music)
- Hello, Samantha speaking.
- Hi Samantha, this is Angela calling.
- Oh, hi Angela, what's up?
- I'm just calling about our meeting today.
I wonder is it possible to reschedule
our appointment in the afternoon?
I have a bit of an emergency
that I need to take care of.
- Let me see, it shouldn't
be too much of a problem.
- I'm really sorry.
I hope it doesn't
inconvenience you too much.
It's just this thing came up and...
- Angela, you know what, I can't
make it to our meeting either.
Why don't we postpone it
tomorrow afternoon at the same time?
- Sounds great, see you tomorrow.
- Angela, Angela, look up.
See that lady over there who's
trying on a red leather jacket?
Isn't that Samantha?
- What?
- No wonder she told me she
couldn't make it to the meeting.
- Oh no, I think she saw me.
(upbeat music)
- So there, okay, have
you ever canceled an
appointment like this
under false pretenses?
- So for a fake reason?
- Or fake reason to go shopping?
- Um, well I may not have,
you know, told my boss
so I can't make it to a meeting
because this thing came up
and then I really was going
shopping and I've never done that.
But how about you, Marco?
- Well, you know, an Ecuador
soccer's a really big thing.
- Right.
- So when we were playing in the
World Cup, Ecuador was playing and...
- Not you, but.
- Well, no, like the
Ecuadorian soccer team.
I canceled an appointment because
I was gonna go watch the game.
- Really, a business appointment.
- A business appointment.
- Well, I guess that's okay.
- Yeah, I mean, it was like the first time
we were ever in the
World Cup and, you know,
my boss didn't really
put up much of a fight
because I guess he also
wanted to go watch the game.
- So very similar to the
events in this dialogue.
- Very similar.
- I guess that's kind of
the inspiration behind it.
- All right guys, I hope you
found some of these phrases
helpful and useful.
And remember, if you have any
questions about anything you heard
in today's lesson, please visit
our website at EnglishPod.com.
- Right, there you'll be
able to find more resources
and also a large
community to interact with.
- Yes, including me and Marco.
- Right, so we'll see you there.
Until then, it's...
- Bye.
(upbeat music)